<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on JM</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on JM</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday Shiny App: Nuclear Explosions</title>
      <link>/2019/12/01/tidy-tuesday-shiny-app-nuclear-explosions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/01/tidy-tuesday-shiny-app-nuclear-explosions/</guid>
      <description>1 Introduction 2 The data 2.1 Sources 2.2 Data cleaning  3 What I learned along the way 4 Useful resources 5 Conclusion   1 Introduction It’s been a long time since my last post, but I’m here again: this time with a Shiny App. Shiny is defined as a “Web Application Framework for R”.
From ?shiny:
  Shiny makes it incredibly easy to build interactive web applications with R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux on a Lenovo IdeaPad U410 (2)</title>
      <link>/2019/04/04/linux-on-a-lenovo-ideapad-u410-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/04/linux-on-a-lenovo-ideapad-u410-2/</guid>
      <description>1 Introduction 2 Back up(s) 3 Update Windows 4 Update the BIOS version 5 Disable UEFI 5.1 Press the “novo” button 5.2 Select BIOS setup 5.3 Navigate tabs and select the “Boot” tab 5.4 Save changes and exit  6 Create a bootable USB stick with your favourite distro 7 Install Linux 8 Conclusion   1 Introduction This is part 2 of the migration from Windows to Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux on a Lenovo IdeaPad U410 (1)</title>
      <link>/2019/02/15/linux-on-a-lenovo-ideapad-u410/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/15/linux-on-a-lenovo-ideapad-u410/</guid>
      <description>1 Introduction 2 Some history 3 Initial steps 4 Windows updates 5 Conclusion   1 Introduction Hi again! This is the first of a series of posts related to my recent journey from Windows to Linux. This first post will cover the reasons why I decided to migrate to Linux and further posts will explain the process. I also want to state beforehand that this post will be highly bias against Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARIMA from scratch</title>
      <link>/2018/12/31/arima-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/31/arima-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>1 Introduction 2 The data 2.1 First analysis: time plot  3 Transformations 3.1 Variance stabilization transformation 3.2 Trend removal 3.2.1 Non-seasonal differentiation 3.2.2 Seasonal differentiation  3.3 Stationary data  4 Model fitting and cross-validation 4.1 Model selection  5 Forecast 6 More plots: Original data + forecast   1 Introduction Hi there! This post is a modification of the final project I did for my Time Series class and the idea is simple: fit an ARIMA model and make a forecast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When does the F-test reduce to a t-test?</title>
      <link>/2018/10/29/when-does-the-f-test-reduce-to-t-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/29/when-does-the-f-test-reduce-to-t-test/</guid>
      <description>If you have taken a regression or design of experiments class (or both), you probably have come across the following problem (or a similar one):
“Show that the sum-of-squares decomposition and F-statistic reduces to the usual equal-variance (pooled) two sample t-test in the case of \(a = 2\) treatments - with the realization that an \(F\) statistic with \(1\) (numerator) and \(k\) (denominator) degrees of freedom is equivalent to a \(t\) statistic with \(k\) degrees of freedom, viz, \(F_{1, k} = t_{k}^2\)”</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>