<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on JM</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on JM</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Establecimientos educativos en Argentina</title>
      <link>/2020/05/25/establecimientos-educativos-en-argentina/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/25/establecimientos-educativos-en-argentina/</guid>
      <description>1 Introducción 2 Mapa 3 Geolocalización 4 Contribuir 4.1 Encontrar una escuela mal geolocalizada 4.2 Ir a Google Maps 4.3 Click derecho: ¿Qué hay aquí? 4.4 Buscar el repositorio 4.5 Ir a correcciones 4.6 Editar el archivo  5 Conclusión 6 Links útiles   1 Introducción ¿Cuántos establecimientos educativos hay en Argentina? De acuerdo al Padrón Oficial de Establecimientos Educativos hay 63390, de gestión estatal y privada. Esto incluye escuelas, institutos, centros de capacitación, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 reporte de movilidad de Google</title>
      <link>/2020/05/10/covid-19-reporte-de-movilidad-de-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/10/covid-19-reporte-de-movilidad-de-google/</guid>
      <description>1 Introducción 2 Sobre los datos 2.1 Movilidad 2.2 Línea base 2.3 Categorias  3 Bajar y procesar los datos 4 Gráficos 5 Conclusion   1 Introducción Hola! Durante esta pasada semana encontré este data set de Google sobre la movilidad en tiempos del COVID-19. Me pareció muy interesante y decidí crear una shiny app para explorarlo en forma interactiva.
Link aquí: https://canovasjm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First year using Linux</title>
      <link>/2020/02/14/first-year-using-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/14/first-year-using-linux/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a year since I installed Linux for the first time and I think it’s a good time to make a quick recap of what happened since then. Everything started here and here
Disclaimer: It is also a good time to recall that all opinions here expressed are my own and do not represent those of my employer. Continue reading means you agree with this.
No more Windows Updates Now I’m able to see what updates are going to be installed and how long are they going to take.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy you own Shiny Server on Azure</title>
      <link>/2020/01/08/deploy-you-own-shiny-server-on-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/01/08/deploy-you-own-shiny-server-on-azure/</guid>
      <description>1 Introduction 2 Create a VM in Microsoft Azure 3 Log in into the VM 3.1 Get the public IP of your VM 3.2 Open a Terminal 3.3 Connect to the VM 3.4 That’s so cool, but I’m on Windows… how can I proceed?  4 Time to instalaR 4.1 Add Extra Packages for Enterprise Linux (EPEL) 4.2 Install R 4.3 Install R {packages} 4.4 Download and install Shiny Server  5 Enable port 3838 6 Put your Shiny app in the server 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday Shiny App: Nuclear Explosions</title>
      <link>/2019/12/01/tidy-tuesday-shiny-app-nuclear-explosions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/12/01/tidy-tuesday-shiny-app-nuclear-explosions/</guid>
      <description>1 Introduction 2 The data 2.1 Brief description 2.2 Sources  3 What I learned along the way 3.1 The use of %in% from base R 3.2 The use of mapvalues() from {plyr} 3.3 Timelines with {timevis} package  4 Useful resources 5 Conclusion   1 Introduction It’s been a long time since my last post, but I’m here again: this time with a Shiny App. Shiny is defined as a “Web Application Framework for R”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux on a Lenovo IdeaPad U410 (2)</title>
      <link>/2019/04/04/linux-on-a-lenovo-ideapad-u410-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/04/linux-on-a-lenovo-ideapad-u410-2/</guid>
      <description>1 Introduction 2 Back up(s) 3 Update Windows 4 Update the BIOS version 5 Disable UEFI 5.1 Press the “novo” button 5.2 Select BIOS setup 5.3 Navigate tabs and select the “Boot” tab 5.4 Save changes and exit  6 Create a bootable USB stick with your favourite distro 7 Install Linux 8 Conclusion   1 Introduction This is part 2 of the migration from Windows to Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux on a Lenovo IdeaPad U410 (1)</title>
      <link>/2019/02/15/linux-on-a-lenovo-ideapad-u410/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/15/linux-on-a-lenovo-ideapad-u410/</guid>
      <description>1 Introduction 2 Some history 3 Initial steps 4 Windows updates 5 Conclusion   1 Introduction Hi again! This is the first of a series of posts related to my recent journey from Windows to Linux. This first post will cover the reasons why I decided to migrate to Linux and further posts will explain the process. I also want to state beforehand that this post will be highly bias against Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARIMA from scratch</title>
      <link>/2018/12/31/arima-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/31/arima-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>1 Introduction 2 The data 2.1 First analysis: time plot  3 Transformations 3.1 Variance stabilization transformation 3.2 Trend removal 3.2.1 Non-seasonal differentiation 3.2.2 Seasonal differentiation  3.3 Stationary data  4 Model fitting and cross-validation 4.1 Model selection  5 Forecast 6 More plots: Original data + forecast   1 Introduction Hi there! This post is a modification of the final project I did for my Time Series class and the idea is simple: fit an ARIMA model and make a forecast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When does the F-test reduce to a t-test?</title>
      <link>/2018/10/29/when-does-the-f-test-reduce-to-t-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/29/when-does-the-f-test-reduce-to-t-test/</guid>
      <description>If you have taken a regression or design of experiments class (or both), you probably have come across the following problem (or a similar one):
“Show that the sum-of-squares decomposition and F-statistic reduces to the usual equal-variance (pooled) two sample t-test in the case of \(a = 2\) treatments - with the realization that an \(F\) statistic with \(1\) (numerator) and \(k\) (denominator) degrees of freedom is equivalent to a \(t\) statistic with \(k\) degrees of freedom, viz, \(F_{1, k} = t_{k}^2\)”</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>