<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on jmcanovas</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on jmcanovas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux on a Lenovo IdeaPad U410 (1)</title>
      <link>/2019/02/15/linux-on-a-lenovo-ideapad-u410/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/15/linux-on-a-lenovo-ideapad-u410/</guid>
      <description>Hi again! This is the first of a series of posts related to my recent journey from Windows to Linux. This first post will cover the reasons why I decided to migrate to Linux and further posts will explain the process. I also want to state beforehand that this post will be highly bias against Windows. Continue reading to see why. Let’s get started.
Some history I bought this Lenovo IdeaPad U410 in January 2013 and spent US$729.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ARIMA from scratch</title>
      <link>/2018/12/31/arima-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/31/arima-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>Hi there! This post is a modification of the final project I did for my Time Series class and the idea is simple: fit an ARIMA model and make a forecast. To do so in R we can use auto.arima() function from forecast package or we can decide what model are we going to fit and why. We will choose the latter path :)
Here we are going to explore how the number of domestic air passengers in Argentina has evolved in the last years, fit a model to the data, and forecast the number of domestic passengers for the next twelve months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When does the F-test reduce to a t-test?</title>
      <link>/2018/10/29/when-does-the-f-test-reduce-to-t-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/10/29/when-does-the-f-test-reduce-to-t-test/</guid>
      <description>If you have taken a regression or design of experiments class (or both), you probably have come across the following problem (or a similar one):
“Show that the sum-of-squares decomposition and F-statistic reduces to the usual equal-variance (pooled) two sample t-test in the case of \(a = 2\) treatments - with the realization that an \(F\) statistic with \(1\) (numerator) and \(k\) (denominator) degrees of freedom is equivalent to a \(t\) statistic with \(k\) degrees of freedom, viz, \(F_{1, k} = t_{k}^2\)”</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>